Late summer, 1942.
1942年，仲夏
World War II enters its 4th year.
第二次世界大战已进入第4年
Hitler's armies occupy most of Europe and part of North Africa.
希特勒占领了差不多整个欧洲 和北非部分地区
Russia faces its second large offensive of the summer.
在苏联，第二轮夏季攻势正在展开
Its goal: The Caspian Sea and the oil fields of the Caucus region.
它的目标是里海和高加索油田
General Paulus' 6th Battalion moves quickly towards the cities of the
保罗斯将军率领第6兵团，已攻占了伏尔加河的一些城市
Volga, where the bloodiest massacre this century is about to take place:
并开始了本世纪最惨烈的战役
Stalingrad.
――斯大林格勒战役
Porto Corvo (Italy), August of 1942.
Porto Corvo (Italy), August of 1942.
Hearts are trump.
红心是王牌
Yes, Lieutenant.
对，中尉
Onward and upward.
继续出牌吧
It's warm. It tastes like piss.
这东西热的，味道像屎一样
- You'll roast in the sun. - Butter for the fish...
别被阳光灼伤，要在身上涂点油
- That's enough, Lupo. - Have a seat.
- 陆保，够了 - 坐下吧
Excuse me, Lieutenant.
中尉，对不起
No, you need spades, not hearts. Play a spade.
不，你要黑桃，不是红心. 出黑桃吧
Onward and upward, Rollo.
继续出牌吧，罗路
Can I dry you off?
我帮你擦干
- This one's mine. - No, no. - Why not?
- 这是我的了 - 不……为什么？
- Who won? - I did.
- 谁赢了？ - 是我
Fritz, when are you going to throw out that camel piss?
费茨，你打算何时扔掉那骆驼尿？
It was a going-away present. For ten marks I can get you one.
这是10个马克买来的礼物，我可给你1瓶
For ten marks I'd buy a whole damn palm tree and plant it on your head.
10马克我可买棵棕榈树种在你头上
Whatever, you always get the best cards... And I'm horny as hell.
你总能拿到最好的牌，我真倒霉
I told you to leave him at the hospital, but no...
我叫你留他在医院，你却……
Oh, God, sometimes I think...
哦，天哪，有时我在想
the Tommies smashed your head instead of his.
是不是英军把你的脑子换到他头上去了
It's his last day.
是他最后一天
- Let him play. - His old lady's in for a surprise.
- 让他玩吧 - 他的太太定会很惊喜
Lupo!
路保
The doctor told him not to drink.
医生说他不能喝酒
- He's gonna have a headache anyway. - Good Italian wine.
- 他只不过是头痛罢了 - 意大利酒太好了
What time is it?
几点了？
Around 1:00. We can still find a whore, right Lieutenant?
1点整. 我们还能去找个妓女, 怎么样？中尉
Look at all those women.
女人还不好找吗？
- And that present for your wife? - That'll just take a second.
- 你太太的生日礼物呢？ - 快寄到了
Battle formation. Hey, comrades, help me with the Lieutenant.
紧急集合. 喂,同志, 帮我照顾一下中尉
Another formation. What a drag.
又是集合，老来这套
Careful! That's my bottle.
这瓶是我的，小心
Careful.
小心点.意大利酒好极了
I can't see anything.
我看不见
What kind of fucking watch did you sell me?
你卖了什么表给我？
Waterproof to 30 meters...
30米防水表
You still gotta wind it, stupid
你仍需上发条的啊，笨蛋
We'll take him like this. Grab the chair.
我们这样抬着他 你们拿着椅子
We'll do it this way.
我们这样来抬
What about my jacket?
谁拿了我的外套？
Come on, guys. Move it.
来吧，伙计们.走吧.
- My jacket. - Where's Rollo's jacket?
- 我的外套. - 罗路的外套在哪？
Careful!
小心!
Men:
各位:
The Fuhrer commends you...
福勒将军称赞你们...
for your fighting in the African Campaign.
在非洲之役表现极为出色
Pushing the English back to the Nile wouldn't have been possible without
把大部分英国人打退到尼罗河
your valiant efforts. Foremost in bravery were the Storm Troopers.
该战役中，突击分队表现尤为出色
You were chosen
你们被选中
because you are the best. Never forget that.
皆因你们是精英 牢记着
New missions now await you.
新的任务等待着你们.
But first,
重要的是,
you will form the core of a new, elite fighting company.
你们将是精锐部队的核心
But before you leave, let me present you,
临行前, 我代表福勒将军为你们授勋,
in the name of the Fuhrer, with a medal for your important role..
以表彰你们
in the heavy and glorious combat at El Alamein
在阿拉曼战役的卓越功勋
Men, this is the new Platoon Commander
士兵们, 这位是新上任的
for Second Company's 1st Platoon.
二连1排排长
Lieutenant Von Witzland. step forward.
韦汉斯中尉，请出列
Those to be decorated...
受勋者...
step forward!
出列!
Battalion, attention!
全体立正!
Right!
好!
Lieutenant von Witzland, decorate your men!
韦汉斯中尉, 接管你的士兵!
Why were you late, Corporal?
下士，你为什么迟到？
Hospital visit. Your predecessor, sir.
到医院探望前任军官，长官
Heros aren't late, Corporal.
英雄不应迟到
Remember that in the future.
记住了
Sergeant,
中士,
do you intend to accept the Fuhrer's award... with your collar open?
你希望这样敞着衣领受勋吗？
- Yes, sir. - The award is revoked.
- 是的，长官. - 他的勋章被取消了.
Battalion, at ease!
全体稍息!
Dismissed!
入列!
Storm troopers, be ready to move out in a half hour.
突击分队半小时后出发
Battalion dismissed!
全体解散!
Don't leave me, men, don't leave me!
别留下我, 别留下我!
Take me with you!
带我一起走吧!
Let's go. Move along.
走吧，跟我来.
Viola!
沃娜!
Good bye, my love.
再见，我的爱
What's up, Fritz? You in love?
怎么了, 费茨? 你恋爱了?
When's the wedding?
何时结婚?
Dearest Clara, Russia.
亲爱的姬娜, 我身在俄国.
Two thousand kilometers separate us.
我们相隔2000公里之遥
The vastness of the distance is overwhelming.
这距离很可怕
I probably won't hear from you again for quite some time.
很久没收到你的音讯了
You should still write...
你应当继续写信...
although it will take a long time for your letters to arrive.
尽管要花很长时间 才能收到你的信.
Will it be hard for you?
写封信对你来说很麻烦吗?
I know if you had your choice, I'd be sitting...
我知道,若你有了新选择, 我此刻并非坐在...
on a leather chair in your father's office...
在你父亲办公室的皮椅上
instead of on a bunk in a freight car.
而是挤在去前线的货车里
Please forgive me, and try to understand my happiness.
请原谅我, 试着去明白我的快乐.
The uncertainty of the last few months has vanished.
近数月的不明朗已消失了
All of a sudden, my life has meaning, a goal.
突然间我感到了生活的意义和目标
Before, everything seemed unimportant...
以前，一切似乎都不重要
but as I get closer to the front, my melancholy lifts.
愈是接近前线，我愈是忧郁
All the feelings I felt unworthy of...
我原以为毫无意义的东西
especially my feelings for you, burn bright again.
特别是对你的感觉，却又油然而生
You should see me,
此时此刻,
sitting surrounded by these stalwart men of ours.
我坐在勇敢的士兵中间.
My men.
我的部下
I love them, because I know that only through hard work...
我爱他们，因我知道要经艰苦奋斗...
will I earn their respect.
才能获得他们尊重
If you were here beside me, you'd probably faint from the smell.
但若你见到他们, 他们的气味定会薰倒你
Can't you count? You gave him the ten.
你不会数数吗？ 你出了10点
Cut him a break.
Cut him a break.
Lupo was delirious, and he played better than you.
路保发疯了, 但他打得比你好
Everybody screws up at first. Don't worry.
开始没人打得好的 别担心
He just can't deal with my brilliant strategy, right Rollo?
他对付不了我，你行吗？
Hey, those are mine!
这些是我的
Not anymore they're not.
别再这样了
Where's this crate headed, anyway?
我们到底要去哪？
How about Stalingrad, gentlemen?
斯大林格勒，怎么了？
Time to teach lvan a lesson.
是该给俄国佬一个教训了
We'll take that city in three days. Cheers!
我们3天内可拿下那座城，干杯!
Do you always look that stupid?
你总是这么傻头傻脑吗？
If I didn't know better... I'd swear we passed this same spot ten hours ago
如果没记错，我们在10小时前经过这里
Russia's big, all right.
俄国很大的，知道吗？
After the war, everybody will get what he wants
战后大家就可随心所欲了
I've already ordered 200 acres and 10 women.
我已订了200亩地，10个女人
Here?
在这？
- Not if you paid me. - Then stay in your lousy little town.
- 不，如果你帮我付钱 - 你还是留在家里吧
Look!
快看!
They're already working for us.
他们已经在为我们服务了
Let's go, men!
大家锄地啊!
Dig faster!
快点!
- How do you say "faster"? - "Davai".
- 你们怎么讲“快点”呢？ - "Davai".
"Davai" and "Ruki vyerkh" is all you gotta know.
"Davai" 和 "Ruki vyerkh" 你们只要知道这些就够了
Adolf will build us a freeway
阿道夫会为我建一条公路
All the way to Kirkov, or whatever you call it.
直通基尔科夫，或随你叫什么都行
This big country is just aching for someone with a fleet of trucks.
俄国会在铁蹄下哭泣
That's enough, Rieser.
说够了，雷瑟
I find it touching that our Lieutenant... is keeping us company.
中尉仍紧随我们，令我万分感动
Permission to ask a question, sir?
长官，我可发问吗？
Go ahead.
说吧
Is this your first time to the front?
这是你首次上前线？
- Everybody starts somewhere, right? - Should be fun.
- 谁也有首次，对吗？ - 真有趣.
Make a bet with you, sir.
跟你打赌, 长官
I come out alive and you don't.
我会生存而你不会
And.. what's the stakes?
好啊，赌注是什么？
From you... two cases of water.
由你... 两瓶水吧
Accepted.
好的
And how's he supposed to pay if he's dead?
他死了怎样还你？
This is pretty.
太好了
And we're not even in Stalingrad yet
我们还没到斯大林格勒
You want me to carry you, Russian pig?
要我背你吗？俄国猪
Move it!
快走!
Get up, you Russian asshole. Go, go, go!
起来，俄国杂种 快走, 快走, 快走!
What are you waiting for?
你还等什么？
Stop it! Leave him alone. Give him a chance to get up.
够了，别打他 让他站起来吧.
Captain,
上校,
I must protest strongly to the behaviour of your men.
我抗议你下属的行为
You want to protest?
你要抗议？
Fine. Go tell the Fuhrer.
好啊.去跟福勒将军讲吧
Lieutenant! Over here!
韦汉斯中尉报到!
Lieutenant von Witzland.
Lieutenant von Witzland.
Storm Troopers Battalion 336, 2nd Company, 1st Platoon.
336号暴风队, 第一军第二团
Welcome to Stalingrad.
欢迎来到斯大林格勒
All the specialists are finally here.
专家们终于都来了
Let me introduce Sergeant Pfluger. Battalion 179.
这是179分队的弗格中士
He just returned from Voronezh.
他刚从沃涅奇回来
I'm pleased you made it on time, Lieutenant.
很高兴你能来
Now let's teach lvan how to swim in the Volga.
让我们给点颜色俄国人看
- Cigarette? - No, thanks! Captain...
- 抽烟吗？ - 不，谢谢
I'd like to report an incident which occurred on the loading platform.
上校，我想报告一件事，有人虐待战俘
I've already heard. It seems you're very fond of the Russians.
我听说了，你好象挺喜欢俄国人
Forget it.
你最好不要
See that the men are issued ammo and grenades as soon as possible.
确保军火和人手准备妥当.
Then officers' briefing. Dismissed.
然后向我报告
Your uncle, Colonel Von Witzland, is a good friend of mine.
你叔叔韦汉斯上校是我朋友
He asked me to look out for you.
他要我照顾你
"God is with us".
"主与我们同在"
It's engraved on every
这句话刻在每个
German soldier's belt buckle.
德军的腰带上
No shit. I hadn't noticed.
妈的，我没留意过
There is no holier work...
没有什么工作...
than defending Western Christian values...
比捍卫基督徒的价值观...
against Eastern Bolshevism.
免受东方的布尔什维克主义腐蚀更神圣
And that's what sets you apart from the Bolsheviks...
这就是我们和布尔什维克的区别...
who have no time for God.
他们背弃上帝
You are never alone,
你们不孤独,
even when deep in enemy territory.
即使是深入敌国
Muller, go!
穆勒，去吧!
Yes, sir.
是，长官
They're crazy. They're killing their own men.
这太疯狂了. 连自己人也炸.
Damned artillery.
去他妈的大炮
Get down!
趴下
He's crazy.
他疯了
Quiet, boys. Follow my lead.
静些，孩子，都听我的
Men, our objective is that factory... at any cost.
我们一定要拿下这间工厂 不惜一切代价
We'll start with that machine gun nest on the right.
首先要压住右边的机枪火力
Whenever the artillery hits, the Russians hide.
无论怎样炮轰，俄国人都躲起来
- Can you see anything, sir? - It looks suspicious.
- 长官，能看见什么？ - 真奇怪
Here, Captain.
这儿，上尉
We're at Frieda 20. Cease fire.
我们在弗里达20公里处 请停火.
I repeat, hold your fire.
我重复，请停火
Where are the five assault cannons?
那5支长枪呢？
We can't see anything, as usual.
什么也没看到, 一切如常
As ordered, Major
少校，下令吧
All clear to the second point.
扫清两处目标
Fire only on my command and maintain silence.
我下命才开火，保持肃静
Understood?
明白吗？
Let's go, men. Follow me!
我们走，跟我来!
Shit!
他妈的!
You klutz, Feldmann.
法曼，你这傻瓜
It's not my fault, Emigholz.
不是我的错
Now lvan knows where we are.
俄国人知道我们位置了
I'm sorry.
对不起
Shit!
妈的
Erwin!
艾荣!
It's no use, boys. He's gone.
没用了，孩子，他死了
Take cover!
找掩护!
He said, they're better than ours.
他说他们比我们强
They don't get jammed.
他们从来没失手
Cheer up!
放心吧
Kill yourself some Russians with it.
快去干掉俄国人吧
Smoke them out.
用烟薰他们出来
Take cover!
找掩护
Hit the foxholes!
干掉这帮混蛋!
Watch the gas tanks!
小心喷火器!
Keep moving, men.
继续前进
We're getting closer.
我们靠近了
Go, guys! Forward!
伙计们，去吧，前进!
What's wrong? You stuck? Move!
怎么了？胆小鬼，快走
That way! Move it!
这边! 快走!
I can't! I can't go!
我不行了! 我走不动了!
Get out of the hole!
快离开这个坑!
Pull yourself together, you fool!
快站起来，傻瓜!
Leave him. Get his tags and let's go.
由他吧. 摘下他名牌让他走吧.
If you don't come, I'm leaving. I can't help you anymore.
若你不来，我便走 再也不能帮你
Go ahead and die, then. It's your fault.
去死吧 这是你自找的
Keep moving. Come on!
继续走.快些!
I told you so, idiot.
我已告诉过你,呆子
Follow me!
跟我来!
We can't make it, Captain
我们不行了，上尉
It's impossible
没可能赢的
Nothing's impossible, Lieutenant.
没有不可能的，中尉
Find a smoke grenade.
找摧泪弹来
Smoke grenades!
摧泪弹!
We got to take out that cannon.
我们要取出那枪
Fritz, smoke grenade!
费兹，摧泪弹!
He's right, sir. We can't make it..
长官，他是对的 我们不能成功..
Feldmann, now you can make up for your mistake.
法曼，你要为自己的过错承担责住
You want your wife to be proud of you when you return, don't you?
你也想回去时妻子为你自豪吧？
Let me go, Captain.
上尉，我去吧
No, I'll go. I won't let you down, Captain.
不，我去 我不会令你失望
I know, son.
我明白，孩子
We'll cover you.
我们会掩护你
Go!
上!
Or else we'd never make it.
我们险些失败
Feldmann owed us.
法曼救了我们
Let's go, men!
来吧!
Now we'll show them.
给他们颜色瞧瞧
Pfluger, take the left. Witzland, take the right.
弗加去左，韦兰往右
We must take this factory
我们要占领这工厂
Forward, men! Follow me!
上吧!弟兄们，跟我来!
Cover us. Shoot anything that moves.
掩护我们 格杀勿论
Let's go, Fritz.
走吧，费茨
Dieter.
戴达、戴达
I shot him.
我射中他了
Shoot me already! Shoot me!
我射的，射我吧
Hands up! Faster! Davai!
举手! 快些! Davai!
- Ruki vyerkh! Now! - Davai! Davai!
- Ruki vyerkh! Now! - Davai! Davai!
I shot my friend!
我射死我朋友!
I killed him!
我杀了他!
- I don't deserve to live! - So what! Now just shut up!
- 我真该死 - 那有什么？闭嘴吧
Don't worry..
别担心..
I did the same once.
我也犯过相同的错
It's normal in close combat.
结束战斗时常常如此
If he'd been Russian, you'd be dead.
若他是俄国人, 死的便是你
Mother, I'm sorry I left you alone.
妈妈，对不起，我要离开你了
Mother, stay with me.
妈妈，我留在此了
What should I do...
我该怎办...
so we can stay together?
才可使我们在一起?
Mother...
妈妈...
Wait.
等等我
Pfluger, come back!
弗加，回来!
Take cover!
找掩护!
Get a gas barrel!
找到个油桶!
Next target: Control room. 6:00 p.m. German time.
下一目标: 控制室 德国时间晚上6时
I need two volunteers.
我需两个自愿者
- We'll go. - Good.
- 我去 - 好
Come on, push!
来，推!
One, two, go!
1、2……走!
We'll get the Iron Cross for this.
我们可得铁十字勋章了
It'll look great on our coffin, Rollo.
在我们棺木上会很好看
Take cover!
掩护!
Shit. Mother'll die if I get hurt.
妈的. 我也会受伤的
Finally, my Iron Cross.
完了,我的铁十字勋章
What are you waiting for? You want to lose another 300 men?
你在等什么？ 想再损失300人？
Forward!
冲啊!
Cover the exits!
掩护出口!
Stay where you are!
站住，别动!
Don't move! Ruki vyerkh!
别动! Ruki vyerkh!
I shit myself.
我尿裤子了.
You're not the only one.
不只你一个.
Radio: I wanted to reach not just the Volga, but a certain..
Radio: 我宁可用另一个方法..
spot on the Volga,
到达伏尔加河,
a certain city.
这个必争之地.
By coincidence this city bears the name of Stalin himself,
这座城市 它刚好以斯大林名字命名,
but that is not the reason I marched there.
但这不是 我进军那里的原因.
It wasn't the name, but the fact that it's a very important point.
它的名字不重要, 重要的是它的战略地位.
From there we cut off 30 million tons
在那里我们可切断 3000万吨商品的运输线
of commerce, almost
of commerce, almost
9 million tons of oil.
包括900万吨原油.
All the wheat from the Ukraine came there before being shipped north.
乌克兰的小麦也经此地 运送到北方及库班地区.
Manganese ore was mined there.
那里有大型锰矿.
It was an enormous shipping center.
它是个巨大的航运中心.
I wanted that city, and in all modesty, now we have it.
我要拿下这个城市.
As you all know, we don't ask so much of you.
你们知道, 我们一向谨慎行事.
We've done it. Only a very few pockets of resistance remain.
我们志在必得. 那里只剩少量抵抗力量.
Some people say:
有人问:
"Why don't you fight faster?" I don't want a second Verdun.
"为何不长驱直入？" 因为我不想那里成为第2个沃登战场.
I'd rather fight with very small combat patrols.
我宁愿和小部队对抗.
Time doesn't matter.
时间不是问题.
What matters is cutting off the Volga.
我们已切断伏尔加河的通道，这才是关键.
We have to keep an eye on Ivan.
我们必须警惕俄国人.
"Small combat patrols".
"小部队"
- What did you say? - Only 62 of us left.
- 你说什么？ - 我们只剩62人.
And for your information,
从你那里得来的消息
we started with 400 men.
我们开始时有400人
Why not tell everyone? Boost morale.
为什么不告诉大家? 鼓舞士气
At least we've got Ivan's stove.
至少我们抢到了俄国人的炉子
Damn stuttering. After every attack
进攻完后很沮丧
Better to stutter
沮丧总比……
than to die..
死了好..
Right.
对
Congratulations. You're still alive.
祝贺你，孩子 你还活着
Have a smoke.
抽一口吧
- I don't drink my courage.. - Asshole.
- 我不用喝酒来壮胆.. - 混蛋
What are you thinking about?
你们在想什么？
I'm not.
没想什么
If you start thinking, you go crazy.
想得多会发疯
So I don't.
所以我什么也不想
Have a swig of this.
喝一口吧
You've got a little switch right here. Just turn it,
你拧一下耳朵，转一下
and you stop thinking.
就不会胡思乱想了
I'm sorry.
对不起
Be glad you can still cry.
你还能哭,该感到庆幸
Go on, cry. It's good for you.
好好哭一场，发泄一下
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
Muller.
穆勒
We've got too many of those. At least until the next attack.
下次进攻之前 我们还有点时间
You're a little go-getter, Muller.
你会活下来，穆勒
GGM
要有勇气
You okay, GG?
好吗？小伙子？
What is it?
怎么回事？
The Russians tried to get a couple of their wounded, sir.
俄国人想拯救他们的伤兵, 长官
so I shot.
所以我开枪
- They'd do the same to us. - Quiet
- 他们会以牙还牙 - 静一下
Can anyone speak Russian?
谁会说俄语？
Me, sir.
我会, 长官
Call over and ask if they want a short truce..
问他们能否休战一下..
to get the wounded.
去抢救伤兵.
Excuse me sir, but that's forbidden. The captain..
但那是不容许的
would never allow it.
上尉不批准的
Shut up, Muller.
闭嘴，穆勒
you stupid ass, you idiot!
你这笨驴，白痴!
I was only telling you our standard procedure.
我只是对你说基本程序
Nobody in this city cares
没人会搭理
about standard procedure.
这基本程序的
Go ahead, Wölk. That's an order.
禾克，去吧 这是命令
Our Lieutenant asks
我们的中尉请求
do you want to get the wounded?
停火拯救伤兵
(speaking russian)
(俄语)
We have to go first.
我们要先出去
I'm not going out there.
我不会出去
Me neither.
我也不会
- Emigholz. - Yes, sir.
- 艾格 - 长官，我在
Pass it on: short cease-fire.
传讯说：开始休战
We'll need medics.
召集医疗员
Bee one to beehive. Cease fire. We need medics.
密蜂一号呼叫蜂巢 暂时停火，我们要医疗员
I'll go with you.
长官，我和你一起去吧
You'd better stay.
你最好留下
You're better off here.
你很好
You look like my son.
很像我儿子
- How old's your son? - Three.
- 你儿子多大？ - 3岁
Let me go.
让我走
It's me. Kolya.
是我. Kolya.
I'll help you. Don't die.
我会帮你.要挺住.
Sons of bitches!
你这杂种!
Cover them!
掩护他们!
Aim for the windows!
打破那些窗!
God damn it!
该死!
Hand grenade!
手榴弹!
- Shoot, Wölk! - Move clear!
- 魏克，开枪!
Don't shoot! Hold your fire!
别开枪! 停火!
You'll get an Iron Cross for that, sir.
长官，你会因此得十字勋章
Who opened fire?
谁先开火的？
Quiet, boy.
大家安静
The Russians were going to attack. When I saw them, I shot.
那些俄国人先攻击. 我见到便开了枪.
- You're full of shit! - He's right, Lieutenant.
- 鬼话连篇 - 中尉，他说得对
I should court-martial you.
你该受军事法庭审判
Go ahead, sir.
试试吧，长官
I'll tell about illegal contact with the enemy!
我会说你与敌人私通!
We don't need a court, sir.
我们不需法庭, 长官
Just give him to the Russians.
把他交给俄国人
You'll get in the newspaper.
随后他就会上报纸
The obituary column.
在讣闻版
Asshole.
混蛋
Emigholz, you asshole!
艾格，混帐!
Always sleeping.
就知道睡
My shaving kit.
我的剃须刀呢？
Who's got my shaving kit?
谁拿了我的剃须刀？
You're still the prettiest.
你已经够帅了
You should model for the cover of Today's Army
可上“今日军人”封面做模特
Grub's here!
到这里来!
False alarm.
警报错误
They were shooting at the grub.
他们在向树丛射击
Mails! Great! Let's have them.
有信! 拿过来
What did they bring us?
没我的信？
Horseshit again.
又是马粪一样
Those guys are fucking insane.
他们一定有毛病
They should eat this crap themselves.
他们该自己试试这些食物
Quit complaining, Rollo.
别抱怨了，罗路
Yeah, I know.
我明白
We're the beasts who invaded Russia.
我们是侵略俄国的野兽
Rollo, I got something for you.
罗路，我有东西给你
No mail?
今天没有信？
She wrote me again that she's had a boy.
妈的，她又说她有了别的男人
That was in her last letter.
上封信就提过
But not a word about the cow that's supposed to calve.
不过没说奸夫的事
Oh, well. She's not the brightest... She wasn't good in school either.
反正她也不是最好的... 连校花也算不上
But the smallest.
但她真的挺可爱
- He married a dwarf. - So what?
- 她嫁了个懦夫 - 又能怎样?
At least she loves me.
至少她爱我.
If only I knew that my cow was okay.
我只关心我的牛没事就好
Listen up.
听这个
Someone's been stealing our eggs.
有人偷我们的鸡蛋
They should hang the bastard.
真该吊死
Look who's talking.
你建议啊
- You loot every Russian corpse. - That's different.
- 你连俄国人的尸体也不放过 - 那不一样
We're at war. They're not at war back home.
这是战争 They're not at war back home.
Here's a letter for you.
这儿有你的信
Asshole.
混蛋
From your wife?
妻子写的？
She's at home guarding our furniture.
她在家里保护家具
Schalke beat Hannover 3 to 1.
沙尔克赢了汉诺威，3比1
Alemania lost again.
阿拉马又输了
That's in your letter?
你从信里看来的？
After the war, I'm gonna play for Werder Bremen..
对，打完仗后， 我要为不莱梅队踢球..
I've already tried out.
我通过试训了
Soccer's bullshit.
足球算个屁
I have a rowboat. A two-seater.
我有条划艇，双座的
My old lady rows while I relax.
我休息时由妻子划
By evening, she's tired and quiet.
到夜里她累了就安静了
I have one too.
我也有一只
Hares or rabbits?
是家兔还是野兔？
Big.
它很大
Your boots... nails bad.
你的靴子坏了
Much cold...
俄国的冬天...
Russian winter.
太冷了
I can fix them.
我能修好它
Me cobbler. Father cobbler.
我是鞋匠 我爸也是鞋匠
Grandfather cobbler.
爷爷也是鞋匠
Quiet! How do you say "quiet" in Russian?
安静! 俄语“安静”怎讲？
Let them sing. It sounds nice.
让他们唱吧.很好听.
Poppy bread.
红面包
Hey, Rollo.
嘿, 罗路
Granddad sent me beeswax. Cure for rheumatism.
祖父寄给我蜂蜡 可治风湿，很不错的
Something happen at home?
家里出事了？
Bomber attack?
被轰炸？
You could say that.
你可以这样说
While I'm risking my ass for the fatherland,
我在为国家拼命
she shacks up with a Frenchman.
她竟然跟法国佬私奔
A P.O.W.!
是名战俘!
That's illegal.
那是违法的
Are you sure?
你肯定吗?
Maybe it's just a rumor.
也许是谣传
She wrote me personally.
她亲自写信告诉我的
Wanted to tell me personally.
她告诉我她的私事
We beat the French in six weeks.
我们6周内便打败法国人
She's afraid, of course.
当然，她很害怕
I'll make the Russians pay for this.
我要俄国人付出代价
But he's French.
但他是法国人呀
Who gives a fuck?
我不管
- What's up? - Nothing. Drop it!
- 有何不妥？ - 没什么，少管闲事!
His wife's fucking around. It's better nobody knows.
他太太离开了他 别让其他人知道
Kiss my ass!
操你们的!
You all hate me!
你们都讨厌我!
Especially you, Lieutenant! You think I'm a country fool!.
中尉，特别是你! 当我是乡下佬!
Rohleder..
罗路..
- Leave me alone. - You're my best man
- 别理我 - 你是我最好的部下
Without you, we'd be dead already.
没有你，我们早都死了
You'd have won your bet.
你赌赢了
- Rohleder! Reiser! - Here..
- 中尉! - 这里..
Lieutenant, follow us!
跟我们来!
Wölk, Pflüger, cover the doors!
掩护住门口!
Damn it, Pflüger, cover the doors!
妈的，掩护着门口!
Russians everywhere.
俄国人到处都是.
We've got to go down there, or they'll cut us off.
我们要突围, 否则便被截断.
Reiser!
费茨!
Here, sir.
长官，在
There's no contact, sir.
长官，联络不上
Get your flamethrowers! Go!
取喷火筒!去吧!
Just us, sir?
只有我们？
Emigholz and I will follow. Wölk!
艾格及我会随后来，禾克!
Yes, sir.
是，长官
Stay here. If we're not back in two hours, break through.
留在此 2小时后仍不见我们，突围走
- Time check? - 7:00 a.m. German time.
- 对时间 - 德国时间早上7点
Why me? I'm the radio man.
为何选我？ 我只是个通讯兵
Sir, let me go along.
长官，让我跟你去
- What the hell for? - Let him come. He might bring us luck.
- 为什么？ - 准许他吧，他可能带给我们好运
Fine. Emigholz, the flamethrowers.
好吧 艾格,喷火器来了
Hands up! Get them up!
快些起来!
You're surrounded. If I scream,
到处都是我们的人 要是我叫喊
you're dead.
你死定了
And so are you.
你也一样
At least say it properly.
我要说……
Is he dead?
他死了？
He's dead, all right. You're experts at killing.
是的,他死了. 你们只知道杀戮
Quiet, or I'll shoot you.
安静，否则杀死你
Shoot me and you'll die. You'd never get out of here.
射我你便死 你永不能离开此地
Come.
过来
- That's the wrong way. - Don't try...
- 走错路了 - 别尝试去...
How about a truce?
可否休战？
I help you find your people, and you let me go.
我助你找队友 你便放我走
Why should I trust you?
我为何要信你？
I could have killed you.
我有能力杀你
With this?
凭这个？
Yes, with that.
是的
Wait!
等等!
What's in your other boot?
你的靴子藏了什么？
My spoon.
我的勺子
You want that too, Lieutenant?
中尉，你也要吗？
How do you know German?
你怎么会德文？
All right. You have my word as an officer.
好吧 我以军官身份守约
If you get me out of here, I'll let you go.
若你带我走 我便放你
You go first.
你先行
Of course.
当然
Slowly.
慢慢走
- Are you all right? - Shit, Reiser.
- 你没事吧？ - 见鬼
We've got to keep moving.
我们要继续走
Thanks, Reiser. I won't forget it.
谢谢，费兹，我会记得的
And Emigholz?
艾米在那？
- Help me! - There he is.
- 救我! - 他在那儿
My leg!
我的腿!
Quiet! If he doesn't shut up, I'll kill him myself.
安静! 再不闭嘴我就杀了他
Your leg's fine.
你的腿没事
That's good, Muller.
很好，穆勒
Keep moving. We have to get out of here.
继续走 我们要离开此地
Move, men! Keep going!
伙计们,继续走!
- Were Germans here? - They went that way.
- 德国人呢？ - 他们朝那边去了
Be careful, girl.
小心点，孩子们
Thanks, Uncle.
谢谢你，舅舅
Medic!
梅迪!
What's going on?
怎么回事？
Who's helping the wounded?
谁在照顾伤员？
Who knows? The Russians broke through somewhere.
谁知道？俄国人从某处攻入了
The Romanians, I think.
还有该死的罗马尼亚人
- Get me out of here. - Lie down.
- 我要离开这里 - 躺下
- Hold still. I'll get a doctor. - Where are my boots?.
- 躺着，我去找医生 - 我的腿呢?
- We need a doctor. - I don't know...
- 我们需要医生 - 我不知道...
I need a doctor.
我需要医生
Doctor!
医生!
- I'm not a doctor. - Over here! Move!
- 我不是医生 - 过来，快
Get to work!
快工作!
Reiser, put the gun away!
费兹，放下枪!
And let him die? Let them all die?
让他死吗？ 让他们全都死吗？
- Get to work. - I'm not a doctor.
- 快工作 - 我不是医生
Not another word! Everyone shut up!
不许多说，全都闭嘴!
Get to work!
快点工作!
Edgar, the doctor's here.
爱加，医生在这
Help me.
帮帮我
Drop your weapon.
放下武器
Captain, let me explain.
上校，听我解释
- Explain what? - We just came from the front, sir.
- 解释什么？ - 我们刚从前线下来, 长官
- Shut up. - We risked our life for our comrade.
- 安静 - 我们为同志冒了生命危险
Where are you, Schroeder?
你在干什么？我的袋子呢？
Where's my bag and jacket?
我的袋子和衣服呢？
I expect a report about this unheard-of incident.
我希望见到正式报告
Right away, sir.
我马上去办, 长官
He's dead.
他死了
This can't be..
不要..
All for nothing.
我们是为了什么？
You're all under arrest.
你被捕了
Take their weapons.
缴了他们的枪
What happens to us now?
现在怎么办？
I didn't want this.
我也不想这样
I request to speak with the General Hentz.
上校，我想和将军谈谈
You think you're special?
你以为你很特别吗？
But it's your right, I suppose.
不过这是你的权利
God damned Russian sympathizer.
该死的亲俄派
Take them away.
带他们走
To sum up the situation, gentlemen...
总结局势, 先生们...
we're in deep shit.
我们情况不妙
Day before yesterday, the Russians broke through the north, near Kletskaya.
前天，俄国人攻陷了北边奇斯卡亚一带
And now, they've broken through in the south too.
现在他们又攻陷了南边
They will try to close the circle around Kalach.. sometime today.
他们想完成卡拉奇的包围圈.. 今天某时
If they succeed, we'll be sitting ducks, gentlemen.
若他们成功 我们就被困了,坐以待毙
Keep smoking, Krüger.
继续抽烟，克路格
Captain, You must help me. Some of my men were arrested at the hospital.
上校，你要帮我们 我的手下被扣在医院里了
One of the men was wounded.
有一个受了伤
Reiser lost control and threatened a doctor.
费兹情绪失控，并且威胁医生
Is this a proper report?
这是正式报告？
Captain, we were trapped.
上校，我们被困了
The entire 6th Army is trapped! Pull yourself together.
第6军全都被困了，你算什么？
We're trying to decide the fate of an army,
我们在决定全部人的命运
and you're whining about a couple of men!
你却在为几个人求情!
You can't do this, sir.
不能这样,长官
The men believed in you. They fought for you.
这些人信任你 他们为你而战
Are we nothing more than a flag on your God damned map?
我们只是你地图上的一面小旗吗？
Excuse me, General.
- 对不起，将军
What's going on?
- 怎么了？
It's about the incident at the hospital.
是有关医院的事
I'll have the Lieutenant escorted out.
我会叫人带他出去
Some of my people used force to get preferential treatment..
今天下午，我们的人用武力要求医生治疗
- for one of their soldiers. - Isn't that the young Witzland?
他是小韦汉斯吗？
Nasty business you got yourself into.
你惹麻烦了
Will we be court-martialed, sir?
我们会上军事法庭吗,长官？
This will not go unpunished.
你们会受到处罚
December 1942. The 6th Army's been surrounded 6 weeks.
1942年12月，第6军团被困4周后
You'll learn.
你会学会的
What's going on here? Why isn't..
这里怎么了？
the road open?
没有铲冰吗？
- Look at all those medals. - You like them, Rollo?
- 看他的奖章 - 你喜欢它,罗路？
Ask him if you can touch one.
问他能否给你摸一下
Asshole. It's your fault we're here.
放屁，我们到这里来全是你的错
- Break it up. - Save your strength for the front.
- 别动手 - 把力气留到前线吧
We need every man we can get.
我们需要每一个人
Everyone in the truck.
大家上车
Move it!
快走
You, too.
你也是
But I...
但我……
That's an order!
这是命令!
Since it's Christmas, I'm going..
今天是圣诞, 我打算..
to give every man some bread.
给每人1块面包
But only if you ask me for it nicely.
但你们必须求我
Say "please"..
求我呀..
my former Lieutenant.
我的前中尉
Please.
求你
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Get out of the truck! Out!
下车! 滚出去!
This is insane. They'll never make it to the front.
疯了，这样永远不能到前线
Get out or I'll shoot.
下车，否则我开枪
Shoot me! I don't care!
来吧!射我!
- Leave him alone. - Go to hell.
- 留他一个人 - 见鬼去吧
Ivan'll finish the job.
俄国人会完成收尾
- What's this? - Hermann...
- 什么？ - 希文...
What's are you doing?
你在干嘛？
This man was shirking his duty.
这人在逃避责任
Get out of my sight!
滚出我视线外!
Lieutenant, this is suicide.
这等于自杀
- I refuse. - Then go home.
- 我拒绝 - 那么回家吧
Rollo, I can't take it anymore.
Rollo, 我已受够了，不能再承受
Quiet, men!
各位安静!
We've had it. No more!
向我们开枪吧，我无所谓了!
Shoot us all! I don't care anymore.
向我们开枪! 我什么都无所谓了!
Quiet!
安静!
Listen up.
听着
The Russians tried to drive us out of Marinovka yesterday.
俄国人昨天想赶我们出马里诺夫卡
Knight's Cross.
爵士十字勋章
Despite heavy losses, we held our positions.
虽损失惨重, 我们却能守住
I'm sure the Russians will try it again,
我肯定俄国人还会来
But without your help, the line won't hold.
但若你们不相助, 防线便难守
Why is this position important?
为何这据点重要？
Marinovka is our best chance to break through..
我们可从马里诺夫卡攻入..
to General Hoth's Panzer division
霍夫将军的坦克部队
which is just a few kilometers away.
只隔数公里
And as you all know,
并且你们都该知道
we must break out to survive.
我们一定要突围逃生
I ask you:
我问你们:
Do you want to starve without fighting...
你们想不作战而去挨饿？...
to be responsible for the deaths of 300,000 comrades?
愿为死去的30万同胞负责吗？
Think it over, men. Is it worth fighting for??
想清楚吧,伙计们 值得作战吗？
Some choice.
值得考虑
We're going to make it, Fritz.
费兹，我们会成功的
As long as the Captain leads, we'll fight.
只要上尉带领，我们便作战
But if you fall, all bets are off.
若你拒绝，一切也完了
Agreed.
好吧，我同意
Comrades, we're going to give these prisoners.. a chance to redeem themselves.
同志们，我们要给这些囚犯一个翻身机会
You'll be honorably reinstated after this battle. On my word..
我保证战后你们可恢复职位..
Witzland, give me your word as a German officer that you agree.
以德国长官身份向我表示同意吧
Yes sir, Captain.
上尉，遵命
All right.
好
Get ammunition
取军火
and form two squads.
并分成两小队
Wölk, lead the first squad. Müller, the second. Dismissed.
禾克率领第一队，穆勒率领第二队
Otto, just a moment.
奥图，等等
We don't stand a chance.
我们没机会的
Why not surrender?
为何不投降？
You know what would happen if we did.
你清楚若投降会有何后果？
Do we deserve any better?
我们有更好的办法吗？
I'm not a Nazi, Otto.
奥图，我不是纳粹党员
No.
不
you're worse, you lousy officers.
你比他们更坏，你是混蛋军官
You went along...
你即使...
even though you knew who was in charge.
知道谁是真理，你也不管
I told you what would happen..
我告诉你将会发生什么..
If I live through this,
若我能幸存,
I'm gonna forgive the old lady.
我会原谅我老婆
I had them tell my wife I was dead.
我叫他们对我太太说，我已死了
It's for the best, believe me.
对双方都好，相信我
But we'll make it home someday.
但我们总有一天能回家的
So what?
那又怎样？
I'll tell you a Christmas story.
让我说个圣诞故事吧
Exactly one year ago today was the last time I was home.
去年今日是我最后一次回家
Special Christmas leave
因为我摧毁了三辆坦克
because I destroyed three tanks.
所以获得了圣诞假
My wife and kids
我的妻儿
met me at the station.
在车站等我
They were stranger to me than any of you.
他们比你们更为陌生
She tried to understand, tried to be tender.
她试着去了解, 试着亲近我
But the more she tried to understand,
但她越试着了解我, 越试着亲近我
the more I hated her.
我便越恨她
Finally I ran off
最后我跑出去
and got drunk. There was nothing else to do.
喝得烂醉. 再没有其他可干了
My wife wasn't sorry when I left the next day.
翌日我走时 我太太毫无悔意
Just the children.
仅仅为了孩子
I got back just in time for the new Russian offensive.
我回来正赶上俄国人新的攻势
And I felt like I was home again.
我想再次回到家
The action's in here. Don't bother the officers.
行动在此开始 别烦着军官
We grunts gotta stick together.
我们要共同进退
- I finished high school. - You'd never know.
- 并肩作战 - 你说得没错
Tanks!
坦克!
- Who's got the grenades? - Rollo.
- 谁有手榴弹？ - 罗路
I look like my grandmother.
我看起来像我祖母
- Rollo, grenades. - Have fun.
- 罗路，手榴弹 - 真有趣
Fire!
开火!
Get your ass down!
快趴下!
Where's our artillery?
我们的炮队呢？
You're the artillery.
你们便是
Get out! Get out now!
快走! 快走!
- I want out! Let me go! - Pull yourself together!
- 我想出去，让我走! - 一起拉!
Get down!
趴下!
Rohleder, get back!
罗路，回来!
Come on!
来吧!
Shoot the big guy!
射那大个子!
They fit.
很合脚
God damnit.
该死
I just got used to this arm.
我刚熟习这武器
You okay, Captain?
上尉，你没事吗？
The Russians can only hit my right side.
俄国人只会射我右边
I was lucky.
真走运
It's my last...
最后一支...
but we'll share it, Lieutenant.
我们分享它
Thank you, Captain.
上尉，谢谢
Back to camp, men.
回营地吧, 伙计们
Now we wait for Hoth's army.
我们去等霍夫的部队
We'll take the cannon with us
我们把炮拖走
Where are the horses?
有马吗？
We're the horses.
我们就是
Everybody out! Now!
所有人立即滚出来
Close the door, it's cold.
关上门，冷呀
Leave's been cancelled.
撤退命令取消了
We're staying here.
我们要留下来
You're crazy!
你疯了!
Everyone out!
全都出来!
How often did the Russians make you shit in your pants?
是不是俄国人又让你尿裤子了？
All right! I'm a coward.
好吧! 我是懦夫
I'm scared! This whole thing makes me sick!
我胆怯了! 整件事让我觉得恶心!
Where's my pay anyway?
总之，我得到了什么？
I get 36 Marks a month, and if I don't get it right now..
每月36马克, 并且如果不马上给我..
then I'm going home.
我就回家
- On foot. - Calm down, Fritz.
- 走回去 - 冷静，费茨
The Russian army must be held.
俄军必被征服
The fun's not over yet.
这仗还没完
Come on! Faster!
走吧! 快点!
Move it, you grunts!
出来,懒鬼们!
In the name of the Fuhrer.
奉元首之名
Carry out the order as given.
给他们复职
- Understand? - Yes, sir.
- 明白吗？ - 是,长官
We're not finished, Lieutenant.
我们还没完呢，中尉
Follow me with your men.
你和你部下随我来
Gentlemen...
先生们...
Keep moving! Over there!
继续走!过来!
Fritz, can they do this?
费茨, 他们要干什么？
It's to remind us
提醒我们
which side we're on.
身处何方
Listen up!
听着!
These civilians...
这些人...
are guilty of sabotage.
进行破坏活动
They are to be...
因此他们...
executed..
要受到..
Positions!
惩罚!
They started the killing yesterday.
他们昨天开始屠杀难民
There's no sabotage.
根本没有破坏活动
They're just out of food.
只是为了找吃的
I can't do this.
我干不来
If you don't, GG, you'll be up there next.
若你不干, 下一个被杀的便是你
Nothing we can do. At least their suffering's over.
我们没办法, 至少他们解脱了
I can't.
我下不了手
That boy there. He worked for us.
那个小孩子, 他帮过我们
And for lvan too. Shut up.
也帮过俄国人，住口吧
What the hell's going on here?
什么事？
We must hurry. There are more of them.
我们要快，还有事等着
Captain, you can't do this. I can vouch for that boy.
上尉，你不能这样做， 能否放过这孩子？
You again?
你又来了？
Does the boy appeal to you??
你对他有兴趣？
Remind you of someone back home?
他使你想起家人？
- Child-killer! - Shut up, asshole.
- 小孩是杀手？ - 混蛋，住口
You want to be arrested again?
你又想被捕？
Return to your post.
返回到位置上
- You're an officer. Do something. - I'll handle this.
- 你是军官，听命吧 - 我会处理的
Silence!
安静!
Step forward, Corporal.
下士，你上前来
I'll kill that bastard.
我要杀那杂种
Let him go!
过来!
Let me take his place, sir.
让我替他吧,长官
Come to attention when I address you!
我跟你讲话时你要留心!
Are you refusing to carry out a direct order?
你打算拒绝军令吗？
Let the boy go, sir.
长官，放过那孩子吧
That's enough!
够了!
There's nothing to discuss.
不能讨价还价
If you miss,
若你射失,
you'll be up there next.
下一个被射的便是你
Get back in line,
返回队列中,
Corporal.
下士
Do you want to take command?
你想拒绝命令吗？
And you're from an officer's family.
你是从军官家族中来的
Take aim!
瞄准!
Why doesn't he do something, Fritz?
费茨，他究竟干了什么？
We didn't kill the boy...
我们若不杀那孩子...
so you could let us die out here, Lieutenant.
我们就会被杀,Lieutenant.
If you were too afraid to give the right order...
若你刚才不敢下正确命令...
then at least give it now.
至少现在下令
Let's get out of here.
准我们离开吧
We'll go to the airport.
我们会去机场
Somehow I'll get on a plane, even if I have to wound myself.
会设法上机, 甚至不惜牺牲
Calm down, Fritz.
够了, 费茨.
I'm leaving. I mean it.
我要走了，我是认真的
Do you know what you're saying?
知道你在说什么吗？
That's desertion!
逃兵!
Talk to him, Lieutenant.
让他去吧，中尉
I no longer feel bound by my oath.
我觉得我快要违背军人的誓言
After all that's happened... I think you have a right to leave.
发生这些事后，我觉你有权退出
I'm not going to let you get us in trouble again.
我不会让你再为我们惹麻烦
That's enough! Understand?
够了! 明白吗？
You're not being reasonable.
那不是理由
You're just scared, Rollo.
罗路，你只是恐惧
Kill me.
杀了我吧
You're a sergeant. It's your duty.
你是中士，是你的责任
- Fritz.. stay here! - I pity you, Rohleder.
- 费茨.. 留在这! - 我可怜你, 罗路.
Fight to the end.
仗打完了
You're already dead.
你已经死了
Who's coming with me?
有谁一起走吗？
Say hello to your son for me when you get home.
代我向你孩子问好
What about you?
你们要干嘛？
I know it's crazy, but I can't go.
我知道这很疯狂，但我不能
I really can't.
我做不到
A year ago,
要在一年前,
I would have been first...
我定会抢先...
But now...
但现在...
I'll keep him company.
我会尽责
Good luck.
祝你们好运吧
I think you'll lose your bet with the Lieutenant, Rollo
罗路，我猜你与中尉的打赌会输
Shit. Where the hell are we?
妈的!我们往什么方向？
No idea.
不知道
I'll ask for directions.
我去问路
Where's Pitomnik?
去Pitomnik怎么走？
(speaking russian)
(speaking russian)
Bread!
面包!
Head west...
向西走...
Through the big balka.
穿过大峡谷
Airport at 5 kilometers.
距机场5公里
Thank you.
谢谢你
Come on.
走吧
Fritz!
费茨!
He has a wounded tag.
他有张残缺的字条
You can still read the doctor's signature.
仍可看到医生的签名
"Doctor Heider".
"希达医生"
This is our pass.
这是通行证
It's a free pass home!
凭这签名便可回家!
Everybody look for one of these..
每人都去找一张..
And put on bandages.
放在绷带上
We're wounded.
表明我们受伤
For you, Hans.
汉斯，给你的
Quiet, man. You're not the only one in pain..
安静点，不止你一个受痛苦..
Ah! Powder burns.
啊! 火药灼伤
- Obviously a self-inflicted wound - Close combat. In the trenches.
- 明显是自己弄伤的 - 在战壕肉搏弄伤的
- Take this traitor away. - No, Doctor, no!
- 把这叛徒带走 - 医生，不要!
I can't do this.. They'll catch us. I'm going back.
我怕行不通，会被捕的 回去吧
It's too late for that now.
现在太迟了
- Just don't screw up. - You neither.
只要不气馁，你能行的
At least I'm not the only storm trooper here.
至少我不是这里唯一的游击手
They should take more of us out of here.
他们该多带走我们一些人
We're needed elsewhere.
我们应该去别处
I have witnesses, Doctor!
医生，不要，我有见证人!
What's wrong, son? Fever?
什么事？发烧？
I can't read the signature. Who's your doctor?
我看不清签名，谁是你的医生？
Can't you speak?
你想不起了吗？
Doctor Heider.
希达医生
Excuse him, Doctor. He's in shock. Tank battle.
原谅他吧，医生 他受了惊吓，在坦克大战时
- His best friend was blown apart. - Here you go, son.
- 他好友给炸得粉碎 - 去吧，孩子，吓坏了
For the fever.. You'll be home soon.
你很快可以回家
Keep an eye on him.
看管着他
Yes, sir, Doctor.
是,医生，知道了
Move!
走吧!
Where's the Lieutenant?
中尉在哪？
Hans, we're over here!
汉斯，我们在这儿!
- Be reasonable. - The plane has to unload.
- 冷静点 - 飞机超载了
Over here!
过来!
You pig! Let me through!
你这头猪!让我过去!
You filthy pig!
肮脏的猪!
Here come our heroes. Assholes.
我们的英雄来了，王八蛋
Hans, where are you?
我们去哪？
GG, hold on to me. You bastard. You dirty bastard.
基杰，抓着我 你这杂种，你这混蛋
You could have made it.
你可以成功的
The last German plane left Stalingrad on January 23rd, 1943.
离开斯大林格勒的最后一架飞机， 在1943年1月23日起飞
Comrade!
同志!
Kill me!
给我一枪吧!
Otto..
Otto..
Welcome to our grave.
欢迎来我们的坟墓
Careful! Not so hard.
小心! 别硬来
Are you hurt?
你受伤了？
You know how fragile he is.
你也知他多孱弱
It's only rash.
只是皮疹
He's covered with boils.
他满身是疮
The Captain, he got the worst.
上尉他伤得最重
No planes for you?
没飞机载他吗？
No.
没有
Musky, you old muskrat.
Musky, 你这老鹿鼠
guess who saved your life?
猜谁救了你？
That'll piss him off.
那会使他生气
Leave the Captain alone.
放过上尉吧
My foot.
我的脚
My God damned foot.
痛得要死
I wouldn't do that.
我不会这样做
I told you not to do that.
我已对你说过，别这样做
Great. Now puke on him too.
好了，现在也向他作呕吧
Give me a butt. Give me a damn butt!
给我一支烟. 给我一支该死的烟!
I just don't have any luck with my right side.
我的右边不够走运，奥图
It's nice we can spend a little time dying together.
垂死的时候该高兴些
Play something for us.
奏乐吧
Damn medals.
该死的勋章
Stand up!
起来!
Stand up, men!
起来，小子!
And come to attention.
都注意了
I want a report... Lieutenant.
中尉，我要你写份报告给我
Where is your unit?
你的队员呢？
We're not in the middle of nowhere.
我们不是野蛮人
We shoot looters in the German Army.
我们射杀德军中的强盗
Or have you forgotten?
你忘了吗？
Stay where you are! Stop!
退回去!站住!
GG, GG...
基杰, 基杰...
GG, he can't do this.
基杰, 他不能这样做
You... you can't do this.
你...你不能这样做
Don't die, GG.
别死，基杰
We'll make it home, GG.
我们会回家的，我们就要回家了
Lieutenant, arrest that man.
中尉，逮捕那人
And get me out of here.
并带我离开这
You want a report? The Russian boy's name was Kolya.
你要报告吗？ 那俄国小孩叫哥雅
And this boy's name was Müller.
姓穆勒
Like a lot of others.
像大多数人
You can still make up for this!
中尉，你仍可将功赎罪!
You must be very hungry.
你们一定很饿
I have supplies.
我有军需品
In the white house,
在那白屋子里,
By the theater.
剧院旁边
We'll drive there.
我们可驾车去
Germans don't shoot Germans.
自己人不会杀自己人
I'm an officer.
我是军官
You can't leave me here!
你不能这样对我
I can't believe it.
难以置信
Bastards.
这混蛋
Slow down, or you'll get cramps.
慢点，你会噎住的
By rank. We'll go by rank.
按军阶，按军阶上
You're first, Lieutenant.
中尉，你先上
So, GG. Some for you.
基杰，这是给你的
Dead Rollo...
为死了的罗路...
cheers.
干杯
Dead Otto...
死了的奥图...
Dead Fritz...
死了的费茨...
to our grand offensive.
还有我们的伟大攻势，干杯
Three's the trick
取三注便赢
Hearts are trump!
红心是皇牌!
Hey, Fritz! Hearts are trump.
嘿,费茨! 红心为大
There's a little bit of blood on the back
在黑桃10后面有血点
of the ten of spades, just so you know.
好让你知道
Damn...
该死...
right side.
右边
Three play cards...
3个玩牌...
while the other's getting laid.
而另一个躺着
I'm not pretty enough for you?
对你来说我不够漂亮吗？
I want a woman once more before I die.
我死前想再要一次女人
- You're all that's left. - You could do me one favor.
- 只剩你能给我 - 你可帮我忙
- Shoot me! But you're afraid! - Stop it!
- 杀了我吧!但你没胆子! - 住口!
You've probably got an innocent girl at home.
你家里定有位天真的新娘
Do you love her? Yes? Oh, yes!
你爱她吗？爱？当然了
A German soldier's love...
一个德国军人的爱...
increases with every step between him and his woman.
会随着他与他新娘之距离而增加
But you'll never see her again.
但你永不会再见到她
You poor fool, you've probably never even slept with her.
可怜虫，你可能还没与她上过床
Maybe you should have a taste of Slavic meat after all.
也许你应该找个南斯拉夫女人
There!
这里!
As soft and white as your virgin's!
又软又白，就像你那位处女!
Fuck me and shoot me!
操我、杀我吧!
Shoot yourself, if that's what you want. I'm tired of killing.
给，你自杀吧，我厌倦了杀人
- Get out of here! - No!
- 滚出去! - 不!
You bastard! You dirty bastard!
你这杂种! 污秽的杂种!
I couldn't do it either.
我亦不能这样做
I'm the German's whore. A collaborator.
我是德国人的妓女，一个合作者
Nonsense. They forced you.
废话，他们强迫你的
I should have killed myself.
我早该自杀
I thought that once, too.
我也有同感
Quit slowing down the game.
别慢了下来
- Spades are trumps. - There's some blood on the 10 of spades.
- 黑桃是皇牌 - 在黑桃10上有些血迹
You know us very well.
你很了解我们
I know you through and through.
我对你们了如指掌
My mother was German.
我母亲是德国人
I used to love your language.
我以前很喜欢德语
I'll never forgive myself for that.
我永远不能宽恕自己
I had the strangest dream.
我做了个怪梦
I had to piss, but I couldn't because I was sleeping.
睡觉时我尿急却撒不出来
Fucking dream.
该死的梦
Better than pissing, eh Lieutenant?
好过撒出来，中尉，对吗？
Have some real food.
吃点东西吧
Then try again.
吃完了再试试
I'll teach her to be nice to you.
我会教她对你亲切些
Don't touch her!
别碰她!
I mean it! Nobody touch her.
我认真的! 谁也别碰她
Everybody up!
都起来!
- Rohleder, come here. - Yes, Captain.
- 罗路, 过来 - 是，上尉
- Don't do it, Rollo. - If he doesn't, I'll shoot you.
- 罗路，别理他 - 若他不过来，我便杀了你
Stay here.
别动
You wouldn't hurt your Captain, would you?
你不会伤你的上尉吧？
- Come here. - Yes, sir.
- 过来 - 是,长官
I won't court-martial you.
我不会起诉你们
You were good soldiers
你们是好士兵
until you chose survival at any cost.
但你们却不惜代价求生
Shut up.
住口
Don't move, Reiser.
雷兹，别动
Do you think you'll be able
你们以为
to live with yourselves as deserters?
以逃兵身份能生存吗？
Shut your mouth.
住口
Don't kid yourself. You should know better than anyone
别自欺欺人 要知道你们永远是军人
that you'll always be soldiers, no matter what. The war is your home.
战场就是你们的家
You're already dead.
你已是死人
For two years, I've prayed to be killed.
两年来，我祈求被杀
The flesh melts from my bones...
我已气耗殆尽，我从未动摇过...
and seeps through the rocks. But you know what?
但你知道原因吗？
I put myself back together again,
我夜夜都在反思自已,
every night.
每晚如此
And none of you can kill me.
你们无人能杀我，
None.
没人可以
You used to be an officer!
你也是个军官!
Quit laughing!
别笑!
Where's the front?
前线在哪？
I want a report.
你要写份报告给我
That's an order!
这是命令!
Heil Hitler.
希特勒万岁
Let's get out of here!
我们出去!
Wait, Captain. I'll help you.
等等，上尉 我可帮助你
Fresh air!
新鲜空气!
You're all crazy.
你们全疯了
A short rest, Captain.. Then we'll go.
上尉，稍作休整后便上路
Don't fall asleep, we're going soon.
别睡着了，很快便走
Where's the front?
前线在哪？
What's going on?
发生何事？
General... Sergeant Rohleder, Iron Cross.
将军，我是中士罗路 铁十字勋章获得者
Give me your weapon.
快把武器给我
Come on, give it to me.
快点，给我
I'm a deserter, sir.
我是个逃兵
Don't talk nonsense, stand up!
别说废话，起来!
- Where's the front? - Come with me.
- 前线在哪？ - 你们随我来
Gentlemen...
先生们...
The front. Where's the front?
前线，前线在哪里？
We'll go soon.
我们马上就走
Don't fall asleep.
别睡着
I'm not going to die.
我不想死
You know, Hans, At home..
你知道，汉斯 在家乡..
when you die as a soldier...
以军人身份而死...
at least they're proud.
至少值得家人骄傲
That's something, isn't it?
还算有价值，不是吗？
Siberia? Not me.
西伯利亚？别烦我了
I'm cold enough.
我冻得不行了
I'll get you out.
我带你出去
I'm going with her.
我会跟她走
We won't even get 100 meters,
我们100米也走不了
But what's the difference?
但有何分别呢？
That way.
那边
Let's go. It's dark enough. We made it.
我们走吧，天快黑了，我们能走出去的
The best thing about the cold..
冬天唯一的好处就是..
is that you don't feel anything.
什么感觉也没有
Everything freezes.
一切都冻僵了
It's too cold to cry.
连哭也不能
Get out of here, Fritz.
离开此地吧, 费茨.
I mean it. Go!
我是认真的.走吧!
The best thing about the cold is..
冬天唯一的好处就是..
you don't have to worry about sunburn.
你不用担心被太阳灼伤
Ever been to the desert?
去过沙漠吗？
You'd hate it.
你会讨厌它的
It's so hot.
太热了
you're always sweating.
你总是会流汗
You think you're melting,
你会担心
like butter.
自己像牛油般熔化
The desert is shit.
沙漠是鬼地方
Except for the stars...
只有星星靠在一起...
They're so close.
它们离得如此近
You know?
你知道吗？
More than a million people died in the battle of Stalingrad,
在斯大林格勒战役中，超过100万人死亡
in combat, or of starvation, or froze to death.
大多都是冻死或饿死
Russians, Romanians, Italians, Hungarians, Germans.
包括俄国人、罗马尼亚人、意大利人、匈牙利人、德国人
Of 260,000 German soldiers, 91,000 were taken prisoner.
第6兵团有26万人被困，91000人被俘
Only 6,000 returned to their country years later.
只有6000人在数年后得以重返家园